Finding AId to the Joseph Breck Records, 1916-1951 Archives.Breck.1 Archives.Breck.1
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives
Joseph Breck Records, 1916-1951
Bulk, 1918-1935
1916-1951 (bulk 1918-1935)
Archives.Breck.1
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives
11.0 Linear feet
Joseph Breck (1885–1933) served The Metropolitan Museum of Art as Assistant Curator in the Department of Decorative Arts (1909-1914), Curator of the Department of Decorative Arts (1917-1933), Assistant Director of the Museum (1917-1933) and Director of The Cloisters (1932-1933). He was closely involved with the original building plans and collection arrangement for The Cloisters. Breck was associated with numerous exhibitions, most notably the Industrial Arts Exhibitions (1918-1929). Breck was responsible for many acquisitions primarily in the field of Decorative Arts. A prolific writer, he is credited with over 200 scholarly papers, pamphlets, publications, and lectures in the fields of textiles, sculpture, furniture, as well as exhibition planning, display techniques and presentation. The Joseph Breck Records document his numerous roles within The Metropolitan Museum of Art and includes correspondence and inter-office memos with museum staff, correspondence with collectors, dealers and lenders of objects; article drafts, reports, pamphlets, catalogs and other published materials.
Arrangement
The Joseph Breck Records consist of a single series arranged alphabetically by corporate name, personal name or subject. When received by Archives, they were arranged chronologically and alphabetically within a calendar year.
Biographical Note
Joseph Breck was born in Massachusetts in 1885. He attended Harvard where he majored in Art History and where he also met and formed a life-long friendship with Herbert Winlock, who later became curator and Director of The Metropolitan Museum of Art. Breck wrote for the Harvard Lampoon where his contributions revealed an interest in art. After graduation he traveled to Europe continuing his studies in art with specific interest in the Renaissance and sculpture. Upon returning to Harvard for graduate studies, Breck was encouraged by Winlock to join the Metropolitan Museum. In 1909 he was hired as Assistant Curator to Wilhelm Valentiner of the Department of Decorative Arts. At this time this department encompassed a large collection of objects drawn from a wide-ranging time period and cultures of origin.
In 1914, Valentiner left for his native Germany to fight in World War I, and Breck was promoted to head the department. Soon after he was appointed Director of the recently established Minneapolis Institute of Art. He returned to the Metropolitan in 1917 as the Curator of the Decorative Arts department and Assistant Director of the Museum. The collections and scope of the the Decorative Arts department so greatly expanded that after Breck’s death in 1933 it was broken into three departments: Renaissance and Modern Art, Medieval Art, and the American Wing. (Miller, p.21, Howe pp. 62-63)
In 1932, Joseph Breck was named the first director of the new branch of the Metropolitan Museum, The Cloisters. Though he never lived to see the building completed, Breck was passionate about The Cloisters, and worked intensely on the arrangement of its collections as well as the planning of the structure itself. In his obituary in The New York Times it was pointed out that he took it upon himself to make “a study of further manuscripts and tapestries to find out what flowers were illustrated in Medieval times so that the new Cloisters’ garden might reflect the Medieval spirit." (NYT 8/3/33)
Joseph Breck had a firm understanding and appreciation for not only design but how objects should be displayed. In 1912 at a meeting of the American Association of Museums held at the Metropolitan Museum, Breck, Museum Secretary Henry W. Kent and curator Durr Friedley set up cases and created displays demonstrating two methods: “good” and “bad”. These installation guidelines which featured less crowding, good light, clear lines and glass display cases with muted backgrounds, became the standard for art museum installation. Breck wrote extensively on display and installation with the “purpose of benefitting both historical and visitor point of view.” (Howe p. 138)
Breck was associated with many exhibitions at the Museum. Most notably he was involved, along with Richard F. Bach, in the popular Industrial Arts Exhibitions. His philosophy was that by showing the public well-designed, everyday objects – chairs, tables, curtains – "good taste" could be taught. He stated that these “touch a person more nearly and while a person may not be able to afford a good picture, that it is possible to purchase a good lamp by seeing these examples.” (Miller, p.18)
Though somewhat conservative in his taste, Breck displayed for the first time at the Metropolitan examples of Art Deco and Art Nouveau objects. Acquisitions are among a curator's lasting legacies and Joseph Breck’s were considered “remarkably fine” (Miller, p. 14, 18).
Breck wrote more than 200 articles covering the fields of Renaissance art and sculpture, design of objects, and display and installation techniques. He was the author of catalogues for those subjects as well as on individual artists (Rodin), exhibitions (the Swedish exhibition) and collections (J.P. Morgan & Ballard handbooks). He was also a frequent contributor to The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin.
In the summer of 1933, while on a buying trip for the Museum, Joseph Breck died suddenly of a heart attack, at the age of 48. Shortly before his death, he had been awarded the Legion d’Honneur for his work in the arts.
Considered by some to be a disciplinarian and rather tactless in his manner, Joseph Breck was by-passed by the Trustees for the position of Director of the Metropolitan when it became vacant in 1931. The job went, instead, to his old friend Herbert Winlock (1931-1939). Museum President William Sloane Coffin wrote that Joseph Breck’s influence and taste was felt in all parts of the Museum. “The Morgan Wing, the galleries on the second floor of Wings K and J, the galleries of medieval and Renaissance decorative arts, The Cloisters, and more recently the new hall of medieval tapestries are a standing testimony to his taste and knowledge in installation and arrangement.” (Bulletin, 1933, p.147)
Works Consulted
Howe, W. E.A History of The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1905 – 1941. New York: Published for the Metropolitan Museum by Columbia University Press, 1946. Vol. II
Miller, Craig.Modern Design in The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1890-1990. New York: Harry N. Abrams Publishers, 1990.
Tomkins, Calvin.Merchants and Masterpieces: The Story of The Metropolitan Museum of Art. New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1989. Revised and updated edition.
Various issues of The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Transfered to the Museum Archives from the European Sculpture and Decorative Arts department on January 20, 2012.
Scope and Content
The Joseph Breck Records primarily contain materials generated by Breck in his capacity as head of the Department of Decorative Arts and as the Assistant Director of the Museum. Also present are records created by other members of the Department of Decorative Arts, including the assistant curator Meyrick R. Rogers and Preston Remington who briefly took over after Breck's death in 1933. The collection is composed of correspondence and inter-office memos with museum staff, including Director Edward Robinson and Secretary H. W. Kent; correspondence with collectors, dealers and lenders of objects; article drafts, reports, pamphlets, catalogs and other published material; requests for positions; artwork acquisition "Blanks" which report on objects newly acquired by the Museum; object descriptions and photographs of objects.
Related Materials
Joseph Breck Correspondence Files, Office of the Secretary Records, The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives.
Durr Friedley Records, The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives.
American Alliance of Museums.; American Art Association.; American Association of Museums.; Bach, Richard F., 1888-1968; Blumenthal, George, 1858-1941; Brummer, Joseph; Burroughs, Bryson, 1869-1934; Clearwater, Alphonso Trumpbour, 1848-1933; Davies, Theodore; De Forest, Robert W., (Robert Weeks), 1848-1931; Greene, Belle da Costa; Ivins, William Mills, 1881-1961; Kent, Henry Watson, 1866-1948; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.). American Wing.; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.).; Morgan, J. Pierpont (John Pierpont), 1837-1913; Pope, John Russell, 1874-1937; Post, Chandler Rathfon, 1881-1959; Winlock, Herbert E., 1884-1950; Industrial arts--United States; Industrial design--20th century; Industrial design--Exhibitions; Industrial design--United States--History--20th century
- Joseph Breck Records, 1916-1951
  - Abbott, Gordon., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accessions List., 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acton, Surgey, LTD. (Murray Adams-Acton)., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams-Acton, Murray., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Edward., 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Addresses., 1922-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agencies (For Stenographers & Secretaries)., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aharon, Gregor., 1918-1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alcove in Gallery J9., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Allen, Frederick H (Mrs)., 1916-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Almco Galleries., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Altman, B. & Co (Notes for Catalogue)., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, The., 1922-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Art Association (The American Art Galleries)., 1923-1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Art Association (Data Regarding Furniture Sold by Museum) 1 of 2., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Art Association (Data Regarding Furniture Sold by Museum) 2 of 2., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Art Association (Sale of Museum Objects) - Lists., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Art Association (Sale of Museum Objects) - Old Lists., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Art Association -- Correspondence., 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Association of Museums (1 of 3)., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Association of Museums (2 of 3)., 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Association of Museums (3 of 3)., 1923-1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Ceramic Society., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Design Gallery., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Federation of Arts., 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - American Handicrafts, Exhibition of., 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Industrial Art -- Eleventh Exhibition., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation., 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - American Sculpture -- Loans of., 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Silk Journal., 1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Union of Decorative Artists and Craftsmen., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American Wing., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Andrade, Cyril., 1923-1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Andrews, Gwynne M. (Bequest Of)., 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report., 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report., 1925 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Annual Report., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Annual Report., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Annual Report., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Annual Report., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Annual Report., 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Annual Report., 1932 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Annual Report., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Annual Report., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Annual Report., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Annual Report., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Antikadjian, A., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Antique and Decorative Arts League, Inc., 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Applications for Positions., 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Applications for Positions., 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Applications for Positions., 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Applications for Positions., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Applications for Positions., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Applications for Positions., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Appointments Blanks., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Appropriations., 1919-1932 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Archaeological Institute of America., 1928-1931 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Architectural League of New York., 1922-1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Art Center., 1922-1927 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Articles., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Articles., 1923 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Articles., 1924 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Articles., 1925 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Articles., 1926 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Articles., 1927 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Articles., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Articles., 1929 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Articles., 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Articles., 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1923 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1927 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1928 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1929 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors., 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Avery, C. Louise., 1924-1933 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - A -- Miscellaneous., 1923-1933 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bach, Richard F., 1922-1933 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bache, Jules S., 1919-1930 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bachstitz Gallery., 1922-1933 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Ballard, James F., 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ballard Rugs -- Catalogue & Notes (1 of 2)., 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Ballard Rugs -- Catalogue & Notes (2 of 2)., 1923 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Barella, Dr. Giulio., 1932 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Barozzi, Dino (Photographs)., 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Berenson, Bernhard., 1923-1930 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Beatty, W. Gedney., 1919-1928 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bell, Harold W., 1922-1929 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bell, James F., 1922-1924 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bennett, Miss Francis -- Art Institute of Chicago., 1923 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bequests (Letter from Mr. Robinson)., 1922 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bern, Henry., 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Beshar, A & Co., Inc., 1924-1925 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Binns, Prof. Charles F., 1930 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bingham, Mrs. Harry Payne., 1922-1924 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Biographies -- Department of Decorative Arts (A-D)., Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Biographies -- Depratment of Decorative Arts (E-M)., Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Biographies -- Depratment of Decorative Arts (N-R)., Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Biographies -- Depratment of Decorative Arts (S-Z)., Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Biographies -- Department of Decorative Arts (Miscellaneous Notes)., Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Birnbaum, Martin., 1923-1930 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1918 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1919 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1921 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1923 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1924 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1925 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1926 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1927 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1928 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1929 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1930 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1932 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1933 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Blanks (Gift)., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1919 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1921 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1923 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1924 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1925 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1926 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1927 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1928 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1929 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1930 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1932 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1933 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Blanks (Loan)., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1918 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1919 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1921 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1923 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1924 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1925 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1926 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1928 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1929 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1931 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1933 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1934 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1935 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Blanks (Purchase)., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Blumenthal, Mr. and Mrs. George., 1918-1921 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Blumenthal, George., 1922 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Blumenthal, Mr. & Mrs. George., 1925 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Blumenthal, George., 1926-1929 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Blumenthal, Mr. & Mrs. George., 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Blumenthal, George., 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Boardman, Bradford., 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Boardman, Bradford., 1929 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Boardman, Bradford., 1930-1931 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Boardman, Bradford., 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Boggs, Dr. Anita Maris., 1927 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Boomer, Lucius., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Boston Museum., Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Bourgeois Galleries, Inc., 1922-1926 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Bowman, John J., 1918-1925 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Braun, Dr. E. W., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Breck, Edward (Cousin of Joseph)., 1928 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Breck, Joseph., 1923-1933 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Brook, Arthur H., 1924 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Brown, John Nicholas., 1925-1929 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Brownlow, The Lord., 1931 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Brummer, Joseph., 1922-1930 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Budget For November 1935., 1934 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Budget For November 1936., 1935 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Building Exterior., 1926 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bullock, Calvin., 1929-1932 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Burlingham, Charles., 1927 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Burlingham, H., 1918 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Burroughs, Bryson., 1924-1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Byerley, Blanche A., 1924-1932 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Byk, Paul M., 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - B -- Miscelaneous (Ba-Bj)., 1918-1933 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - B -- Miscellaneous (Bl-Bu)., 1918-1933 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Canessa Gallery., 1918-1929 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Carlhian & Company., 1919-1930 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Carter, Morris., 1927-1932 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Cary, Miss Elizabeth Luther., 1922-1926 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Carrer, Antonio (Photographs)., 1926 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Cassiobury Staircase., 1932 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Chanler, Robert W., 1922-1923 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Chappee, Julien., 1929 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Charpentier, Jean & Co., 1922-1927 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Chase, Prof. Heorge H., 1920-1932 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cheney (Brothers) Silks., 1923-1928 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Churchill, Arthur., 1929-1930 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Cinema Locations and Tapestry Scenario., 1930 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Clapp, Frederick Mortimer., 1926-1932 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Classification, List of., Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Clearwater, Alphonso Trumpbour., 1919-1932 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Clifford, William., 1925-1933 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Coffin, William Sloane., 1929-1933 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Cohen, Dewitt Clinton., 1922-1932 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Coleman, Laurence V., 1924-1928 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - College Art Association of America., 1925-1932 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Colnaghi, P & D & Co., 1921-1923 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Color Prints., 1929 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Color Reporoducations., 1927 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Comings, Lois L., 1925-1929 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Cook, Dr. Walter W.S., 1925-1931 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Coomaraswamy, Dr. A. K., 1926-1930 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Coquillat, J., 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Cornelius, Charles., 1922-1932 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Cornish, Margaret., 1922-1924 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Costume Exhibition., 1932 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Cox, Ewan., 1929 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Cox, George J., 1923 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Cox, Warren E., 1927 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Crichton Bros., 1920 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Crowninshield, Frank., 1923-1926 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Crowther, T. & Son (Photographs)., 1931 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Curtis, Edmund De F., 1922-1929 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - C -- Miscellaneous., 1919-1933 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Daloz, Mme Yvonne., 1930 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Damaged Art Treasures., 1930 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Dana, Richard H., 1922-1933 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Davidson, Henry F., 1918-1933 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Davies, R.N., 1929-1930 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Davis, Theodore M., 1925-1930 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Dean, Dr. Bashford., 1918-1928 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Dean, Mrs. Bashford Harriet Dean (Sister)., 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Dean Tablet (Unveiling of)., 1930 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence After Death of Joseph Breck (mostly personal)., 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Decour, A., 1924-1933 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - De Forest, Lockwood., 1928 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - De Forest, Robert W., Mrs. Robert W. Johnston., 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - De Forest, Robert W., Mrs. Robert W., Johnson, Lockwood., 1922-1923 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - De Forest, Robert W., Mrs. Robert W W., Lockwood., 1924 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - De Forest, Robert W., Mrs. Robert W W., Lockwood., 1925 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Donaldson, Douglas (Donaldson Studio)., 1922-1925 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Douglas, Langton R., 1922-1932 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Downs, Joseph., 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Draper, Dorothy., 1926 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Dreicer, Michael (Bequest)., 1921 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Dreicer Collection - Return of Objects., 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Drey, A. S., 1927-1931 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Duveen Brothers., 1920-1933 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Dyer, Mr. Elisha., 1928 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - D -- Miscellaneous., 1921-1932 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Eastman, Alvan C., 1922-1926 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Eaton, Mrs. J. Shirley., 1928-1929 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Eggers, George W., 1922-1925 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Ehrich, Adelaide; Walter Ehrich; The Ehrich Galleries., 1922-1930 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Eisen, Dr. G. A., 1924 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Eliott, Huger., 1925-1933 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Elsberg, H. A., 1926-1941 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Elwes, Guy (Ltd)., 1931 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Employee's Association, Metropolitan Museum of Art., 1922-1933 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Exhibitions., 1922-1924 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Exhibition Schedules., 1930-1931 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - European Buying Trip., 1926 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - European Buying Trip - Mr. Breck and Mr. Remington., 1931 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - E -- Miscellaneous., 1923-1933 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Fahnstock, Mrs. Harris; Miss Faith., 1922-1933 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Figdor Sale - Figdor Collection., 1930 (Box 11, Folder 26)